Paul Fiesel

paul.fiesel@gmail.com • 703-965-3809 • linkedin.com/in/paulfiesel

Portfolio: fieselmedia.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a professional video producer with over 9 years of experience in creating and developing multimedia solutions for internal and external platforms while maintaining the highest standards of quality. I have a passion for bringing stories to life through every medium with a proven track record of managing complex projects from start to finish.

SKILLS

- Video production
- 3D modeling & animation
- Motion graphic animation
- Video, audio & lighting
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Unreal Engine 5
- Team leadership
- Project management
- HTML/CSS/Javascript
- Corporate consultation
- CMS management
- Microsoft Office 365

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Media Production Manager

Dallas, TX

AT&T 5/2020 – Present

- Design, develop, and implement media for training courses taken by 220,000+ employees.
- Research, prepare and produce audio visual media (graphics, video, animation, or XR components) with info obtained by subject matter experts across the business.
- Plan and execute media development through scriptwriting, storyboarding, location scouting, shot selection, video shooting, sound selection, digital effect creation, final editing and distribution.
- Conceive, produce and manage the creation of 50+ graphic designs, 3D models, web designs, live-video, audio and web broadcasts, and other visual communication.
- Consult regularly with clients and senior executives to assess, build, and update AT&T training courses, resulting in the business saving over \$1 million a year.

Multimedia Designer Alexandria, VA

The Salvation Army

12/2018 - 05/2020

- Created all online content for national publication called "Peer" using HTML, CSS, and Javascript to manage the website via the department's content management system.
- Produced daily video and media content for 30,000+ subscribers and followers.
- Shot, directed, and edited videos of influencers, experts, and officers of The Salvation Army.
- Edited audio tracks and produced podcast episodes for the Publication Department.
- Supervised 10+ contractors and vendors, ensuring a high-level of work quality and deadlines
- Led online relaunch of the magazine's rebrand in January 2019, increasing online following and subscriptions by 60%+ at the end of the first year.
- Engaged daily with 5,500+ followers on publication's social media channels.
- Analyzed magazine's \$3,600 yearly online advertisement budget and generated weekly reports.

Digital Media Marketing Consultant

Fairfax, VA

Direct Development Inc.

3/2018 - 12/2018

- Developed digital content weekly, including videos, graphics, animations to support 30+ clients.
- Analyzed the benefits of video in marketing campaigns, adjusting strategies accordingly.
- Supervised 2 project managers by using marketing strategy to increase online traffic and build relationships with my team's 7 non-profit and higher-education clients.
- Collaborated with the Editorial Manager, Content Strategist, Account Strategist, senior consultants, and other team members on content strategy and planning.
- Executed advertising campaigns and analyzed data metrics in HubSpot every quarter.

- Produced training & curriculum media solutions for 300,000+ employees worldwide with the AT&T University Media Production Team.
- Captured, edited, and finalized 50+ instructional videos and motion graphic content for training courses using the Adobe Premiere, After Effects, Audition, Illustrator, and Photoshop.
- Developed and assisted in the implementation of multiple training programs, job aids, and other performance improvement solutions.
- Partnered with instructional designers when utilizing design best practices to create courses that meet learning objectives and improve learner retention.
- Managed part-time contractors, ensuring project timelines were delivered on-time with high-quality.

Marketing Communications Specialist

Carrollton, TX

Para Systems Inc.

12/2015 - 11/2016

- Created videos, product literature, marketing emails, and web content using CSS, HTML, Adobe Premiere, After Effects, InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Microsoft PowerPoint.
- Collaborated with copywriters and designers of the team to develop holistic marketing solutions.
- Developed and launched integrated, multi-channel print, catalog, web and direct marketing campaigns, resulting in sales-qualified leads for products.
- Built relationships with clients while managing multiple projects at once.

EDUCATION

University of Dallas Irving, TX

B.A. in History (Cum Laude, Provost's Scholarship Recipient)